## Elchin Kuliyev

System Administrator

#### Contact

**Address** 

Baku, AZ1005

**Phone** 

+994505362388

E-mail

elchin.kuliyev@list.ru

#### **Skills**

Linux Operating Systems

Very Good

Windows Operating Systems

Excellent

IT Hardware concepts

Very Good

LAN/WAN networking

Very Good

Virtualization ESXI/Hyper-v

Excellent

Scripting

Good

Security & privacy

Excellent

Monitoring

Very Good

Driven Systems Administrator with 5 years of experience in software implementation and maintenance. Proven history of managing complex infrastructures and data center operations. Expert in solutions-oriented business application problem-solving and dedicated to providing best-in-class service. Skilled at troubleshooting, communication and collaboration.

#### **Work History**

2018-06 -Current

#### **Enterprise System Administrator**

AZERTAC - Azerbaijan State News Agency, Baku

- Monitor the operation of all systems to ensure proper functioning of hardware and software.
  Install and configure servers.
- Administer Exchange Online system, virtual machines, web servers, Linux servers, Windows servers, storage, and database technologies.
- Daily support and administration of Microsoft Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, Group Policy.
- Administration of vSphere ESXi, vCenter Server, vCenter Site Recovery Manager, vSphere VSAN, and iSCSI SANs.
- Maintain regular backups of all servers and verify validity of those backups.
- Identify, research, troubleshoot and resolve problems with hardware, software and IT systems.
- Installation, configuration, and administration of Windows and Linux Servers.
- Monitoring regular backup operations.
- Troubleshoot hardware and software errors.

2019-07 -2021-01

#### **Enterprise System Administrator**

Commissioner for Human Rights (Ombudsman), Baku

- Responsible for the maintenance, configuration, and reliable operation of computer systems, network servers, and virtualization
- Install and upgrade computer components and software, manage virtual servers, and integrate automation processes
- Troubleshoot hardware and software errors by running diagnostics, documenting problems and resolutions, prioritizing problems, and assessing impact of issues

- Provide documentation and technical specifications to IT staff for planning and implementing new or upgrades of IT infrastructure
- Perform or delegate regular backup operations and implement appropriate processes for data protection, disaster recovery, and failover procedures
- Lead desktop and helpdesk support efforts, making sure all desktop applications, workstations, and related equipment problems are resolved in a timely manner with limited disruptions
- Responsible for capacity, storage planning, and database performance

#### 2011-01 -2018-06

#### **Junior System Administrator**

Ukrtelekom, Zaporozhye

- Managed infrastructure upgrades, analysis and resolution of end user hardware and software issues.
- Designed and evaluated WAN and LAN connectivity technologies.
- Created patches and solutions to fix bugs in existing applications.
- Spearheaded inventory control measures to replenish and maintain IT equipment.
- Performed software installations and upgrades to UNIX or Windows operating systems.
- Monitored computer virus reports to determine when to update virus protection systems.

#### **Education**

2014-09 -2018-03 Bachelor of Science: Micro And Nano Electronics

Zaporizhzhia Polytechnic - Zaporizhzhia



# Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate

### **ELCHIN KULIIEV**

Has successfully completed the requirements to be recognized as a Microsoft® Certified Solutions Associate: Windows Server 2016.

Date of achievement: January 26, 2021 Certification number: H655-1958







# Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert

### **ELCHIN KULIIEV**

Has successfully completed the requirements to be recognized as a Microsoft® Certified Solutions Expert: Productivity.

Date of achievement: January 30, 2021 Certification number: H662-8883



